1. The normal form which satisfies multivalued dependencies and which is in BCNF is
a) 4 NF
b) 3 NF
c) 2 NF
d) All of the mentioned
Answer-a
2. Which of the following is a tuple-generating dependencies?
a) Functional dependency
b) Equality-generating dependencies
c) Multivalued dependencies
d) Non-functional dependency
Answer-c
3. The main task carried out in the __________ is to remove repeating attributes to separate tables.
a) First Normal Form
b) Second Normal Form
c) Third Normal Form
d) Fourth Normal Form
Answer-a

4. Which of the normal form is based on multivalued dependencies ?
a) First
b) Second
c) Third
d) Fourth
Answer-d
5. Which forms has a relation that possesses data about an individual entity?
a) 2NF
b) 3NF
c) 4NF
d) 5NF
Answer-c
6. If a multivalued dependency holds and is not implied by the corresponding functional dependency, it usually arises from one of the following sources.
a) A many-to-many relationship set
b) A multivalued attribute of an entity set
c) A one-to-many relationship set
d) Both a and b
Answer-d
7. Which of the following has each related entity set has its own schema and there is an additional schema for the relationship set?
a) A many-to-many relationship set
b) A multivalued attribute of an entity set
c) A one-to-many relationship set
d) Both a and b
Answer-a
8. In which of the following , a separate schema is created consisting of that attribute and the primary key of the entity set.
a) A many-to-many relationship set
b) A multivalued attribute of an entity set
c) A one-to-many relationship set
d) Both a and b
Answer-b
9. Fifth Normal form is concerned with
a) Functional dependency
b) Multivalued dependency
c) Join dependency
d) Domain-key	
Answer-c
10. In 2NF
a) No functional dependencies (FDs) exist.
b) No multivalued dependencies (MVDs) exist.
c) No partial FDs exist.
d) No partial MVDs exist.
Answer-c
11. A relational database consists of a collection of
a) Tables
b) Fields
c) Records
d) Keys
Answer-a
12. A ________ in a table represents a relationship among a set of values.
a) Column
b) Key
c) Row
d) Entry
Answer-c
13. The term _______ is used to refer to a row.
a) Attribute
b) Tuple
c) Field
d) Instance
Answer-b
14. The term attribute refers to a ___________ of a table.
a) Record
b) Column
c) Tuple
d) Key
Answer-b
15. For each attribute of a relation, there is a set of permitted values, called the ________ of that attribute.
a) Domain
b) Relation
c) Set
d) Schema
Answer-a
16. Database __________ , which is the logical design of the database, and the database _______,which is a snapshot of the data in the database at a given instant in time.
a) Instance, Schema
b) Relation, Schema
c) Relation, Domain
d) Schema, Instance
Answer-d
17. Course(course_id,sec_id,semester)
Here the course_id,sec_id and semester are __________ and course is a _________ .
a) Relations, Attribute
b) Attributes, Relation
c) Tuple, Relation
d) Tuple, Attributes
Answer-b
18. Department (dept name, building, budget) and Employee (employee_id , name, dept name,salary)
Here the dept_name attribute appears in both the relations .Here using common attributes in relation schema is one way of relating ___________ relations.
a) Attributes of common
b) Tuple of common
c) Tuple of distinct
d) Attributes of distinct
Answer-c
19. A domain is atomic if elements of the domain are considered to be ____________ units.
a) Different
b) Indivisbile
c) Constant
d) Divisible
Answer-b
20. The tuples of the relations can be of ________ order.
a) Any
b) Same
c) Sorted
d) Constant
Answer-a
21. Aggregate functions are functions that take a ___________ as input and return a single value.
a) Collection of values
b) Single value
c) Aggregate value
d) Both a & b
Answer-a
22. Select __________
from instructor
where dept name= ’Comp. Sci.’;
Which of the following should be used to find the mean of the salary ?
a) Mean(salary)
b) Avg(salary)
c) Sum(salary)
d) Count(salary)
Answer-b
23. Select count (____ ID)
from teaches
where semester = ’Spring’ and year = 2010;
If we do want to eliminate duplicates, we use the keyword ______in the aggregate expression.
a) Distinct
b) Count
c) Avg
d) Primary key
Answer-a
24. All aggregate functions except _____ ignore null values in their input collection.
a) Count(attribute)
b) Count(*)
c) Avg
d) Sum
Answer-b
25. A Boolean data type that can take values true, false, and________ .
a) 1	
b) 0
c) Null
d) Unknown
Answer-d
26. The ____ connective tests for set membership, where the set is a collection of values produced by a select clause. The ____ connective tests for the absence of set membership.
a) Or, in
b) Not in, in
c) In, not in
d) In, or
Answer-c
27. Which of the following should be used to find all the courses taught in the Fall 2009 semester but not in the Spring 2010 semester .
a) Select distinct course id
from section
where semester = ’Fall’ and year= 2009 and
course id not in (select course id
from section
where semester = ’Spring’ and year= 2010);
b) Select distinct course_id
from instructor
where name not in (’Fall’, ’Spring’);
c) (Select course id
from section
where semester = ’Spring’ and year= 2010)
d) Select count (distinct ID)
from takes
where (course id, sec id, semester, year) in (select course id, sec id, semester, year
from teaches
where teaches.ID= 10101);
Answer-a
28. . The phrase “greater than at least one” is represented in SQL by _____.
a) < all
b) < some
c) > all
d) > some
Answer-d
29. Which of the following is used to find all courses taught in both the Fall 2009 semester and in the Spring 2010 semester .
a) Select course id
from section as S
where semester = ’Fall’ and year= 2009 and
exists (select *
from section as T
where semester = ’Spring’ and year= 2010 and
S.course id= T.course id);
b) Select name
from instructor
where salary > some (select salary
from instructor
where dept name = ’Biology’);
c) Select count (distinct ID)
from takes
where (course id, sec id, semester, year) in (select course id, sec id, semester, year
from teaches
where teaches.ID= 10101);
d) (Select course id
from section
where semester = ’Spring’ and year= 2010)
Answer-a
30. We can test for the nonexistence of tuples in a subquery by using the _____ construct.
a) Not exist
b) Not exists
c) Exists
d) Exist
Answer-b
31. We can use the following three rules to find logically implied functional dependencies. This collection of rules is called
a) Axioms
b) Armstrong’s axioms
c) Armstrong
d) Closure
Answer-b
32. Which of the following is not a Armstrong’s Axiom ?
a) Reflexivity rule
b) Transitivity rule
c) Pseudotransitivity rule
d) Augmentation rule
Answer-c
33. The relation employee(ID,name,street,Credit,street,city,salary) is decomposed into
employee1 (ID, name)
employee2 (name, street, city, salary)
This type of decomposition is called
a) Lossless decomposition
b) Lossless-join decomposition
c) Both a and b
d) None of the mentioned
Answer-d
34. Inst_dept (ID, name, salary, dept name, building, budget) is decomposed into
instructor (ID, name, dept name, salary)
department (dept name, building, budget)
This comes under
a) Lossy-join decomposition
b) Lossy decomposition
c) Lossless-join decomposition
d) Both a and b
Answer-d
35. There are two functional dependencies with the same set of attributes on the left side of the arrow:
A->BC
A->B
This can be combined as
a) A->BC
b) A->B
c) B->C
d) None of the mentioned
Answer-a
36. Consider a relation R(A,B,C,D,E) with the following functional dependencies:
ABC -> DE and
D -> AB
The number of superkeys of R is:
a) 2
b) 7
c) 10
d) 12
Answer-c
37 Suppose we wish to find the ID’s of the employees that are managed by people who are managed by the employee with ID 123. Here are two possible queries:
I.SELECT ee.empID
FROM Emps ee, Emps ff
WHERE ee.mgrID = ff.empID AND ff.mgrID = 123;
II.SELECT empID
FROM Emps
WHERE mgrID IN
(SELECT empID FROM Emps WHERE mgrID = 123);
Which, if any, of the two queries above will correctly (in SQL2) get the desired set of employee ID’s?
a) Both I and II
b) I only
c) II only
d) Neither I nor I
Answer-a
38. Suppose relation R(A,B) currently has tuples {(1,2), (1,3), (3,4)} and relation S(B,C) currently has {(2,5), (4,6), (7,8)}. Then the number of tuples in the result of the SQL query:
Select *
From R Natural Outer Join S; is:
a) 2
b) 4
c) 6
d) None of the mentioned
Answer-a
39. . Suppose now that R(A,B) and S(A,B) are two relations with r and s tuples, respectively (again, not necessarily distinct). If m is the number of (not necessarily distinct) tuples in the result of the SQL query:
R intersect S;
Then which of the following is the most restrictive, correct condition on the value of m?
(a) m = min(r,s)
(b) 0 <= m <= r + s
(c) min(r,s) <= m <= max(r,s)
(d) 0 <= m <= min(r,s)
Answer-d
40. Suppose relation R(A,B,C,D,E) has the following functional dependencies:
A -> B
B -> C
BC -> A
A -> D
E -> A
D -> E
Which of the following is not a key?
a) A
b) E
c) B,C
d) D
Answer-c
41. Which level of RAID refers to disk mirroring with block striping?
a) RAID level 1
b) RAID level 2
c) RAID level 0
d) RAID level 3
Answer-a
42. A unit of storage that can store one or more records in a hash file organization is denoted as
a) Buckets
b) Disk pages
c) Blocks
d) Nodes
Answer-a
43. The file organization which allows us to read records that would satisfy the join condition by using one block read is
a) Heap file organization
b) Sequential file organization
c) Clustering file organization
d) Hash file organization
Answer-c
44. What are the correct features of a distributed database?
a) Is always connected to the internet
b) Always requires more than three machines
c) Users see the data in one global schema.
d) Have to specify the physical location of the data when an update is done
Answer-c
45. Each tablespace in an Oracle database consists of one or more files called
a) Files
b) name space
c) datafiles
d) PFILE
Answer-c
46. A top-to-bottom relationship among the items in a database is established by a
a) Hierarchical schema
b) Network schema
c) Relational schema
d) All of the mentioned
Answer-a
47. A technique for direct search is
a) Binary Search
b) Linear Search
c) Tree Search
d) Hashing
Answer-d
48. The searching technique that takes O (1) time to find a data is
a) Linear Search
b) Binary Search
c) Hashing
d) Tree Search
Answer-c
49. The goal of hashing is to produce a search that takes
a) O(1) time
b) O(n2 )time
c) O(log n ) time
d) O(n log n ) time
Answer-a
50. Key value pairs is usually seen in
a) Hash tables
b) Heaps
c) Both a and b
d) Skip list
Answer-a
51. Which of the following scenarios leads to linear running time for a random search hit in a linear-probing hash table?
a) All keys hash to same index
B) All keys hash to different indices
c) All keys hash to an even-numbered index
d) All keys hash to different even-numbered indices
Answer-a
52. Breadth First Search is used in
a) Binary trees
b) Stacks
c) Graphs
d) Both a and c above
Answer-c
53. A collection of data designed to be used by different people is called a/an
a) Organization
b) Database
c) Relationship
d) Schema
Answer-b
54. Which of the following is the oldest database model?
a) Relational
b) Deductive
c) Physical
d) Network
Answer-d
55. Which of the following is an attribute that can uniquely identify a row in a table?
a) Secondary key
b) Candidate key
c) Foreign key
d) Alternate key
Answer-b
56. Which of the following is the process of selecting the data storage and data access characteristics of the database?
a) Logical database design
b) Physical database design
c) Testing and performance tuning
d) Evaluation and selecting
Answer-b
57. Which of the following terms does refer to the correctness and completeness of the data in a database?
a) Data security
b) Data constraint
c) Data independence
d) Data integrity
Answer-d
58. The relationship between DEPARTMENT and EMPLOYEE is a
a) One-to-one relationship
b) One-to-many relationship
c) Many-to-many relationship
d) Many-to-one relationship
Answer-b
59. A table can be logically connected to another table by defining a
a) Super key
b) Candidate key
c) Primary key
d) Unique key
Answer-c
60. If the state of the database no longer reflects a real state of the world that the database is supposed to capture, then such a state is called
a) Consistent state
b) Parallel state
c) Durable state
d) Inconsistent state
Answer-d
61. Ensuring isolation property is the responsibility of the
a) Recovery-management component of the DBMS
b) Concurrency-control component of the DBMS
c) Transaction-management component of the DBMS
d) Buffer management component in DBMS
Answer-b
62. A transaction may not always complete its execution successfully. Such a transaction is termed
a) Aborted
b) Terminated
c) Closed
d) All of the mentioned
Answer-a
63. If an transaction is performed in a database and committed, the changes are taken to the previous state of transaction by
a) Flashback
b) Rollback
c) Both a and b
d) Cannot be done
Answer-d
64. Each modification done in database transaction are first recorded into the
a) Hard drive
b) Log
c) Disk
d) DataMart
Answer-b
65. When the transaction finishes the final statement the transaction enters into
a) Active state
b) Committed state
c) Partially committed state
d) Abort state
Answer-c
66. The name of the transaction file shall be provided by the operator and the file that contains the edited transactions ready for execution shall be called
a) Batch. Exe
b) Trans. Exe
c) Opt. Exe
d) Edit.Exe
Answer-c
67. Which of the following is an atomic sequence of database actions?
a) Transaction
b) Concurrency
c) Relations
d) All of the mentioned
Answer-a
68. If the state of the database no longer reflects a real state of the world that the database is supposed to capture, then such a state is called
a) Consistent state
b) Parallel state
c) Atomic state
d) Inconsistent state
Answer-d
69. _______ means that data used during the execution of a transaction cannot be used by a second transaction until the first one is completed.
a) Serializability
b) Atomicity
c) Isolation
d) Time stamping
Answer-c
70. DBMS periodically suspends all processing and synchronizes its files and journals through the use of
a) Checkpoint facility
b) Backup facility
c) Recovery manager
d) Database change log
Answer-a
71. Which of the following is not a state in transaction ?
a) Active
b) Terminated
c) Aborted
d) Partially committed
Answer-b
72. A system is in a ______ state if there exists a set of transactions such that every transaction in the set is waiting for another transaction in the set.
a) Idle	
b) Waiting
c) Deadlock
d) Ready
Answer-c
73. The deadlock state can be changed back to stable state by using _____________ statement.
a) Commit
b) Rollback
c) Savepoint
d) Deadlock
Answer-b
74. What are the ways of dealing with deadlock ?
a) Deadlock prevention
b) Deadlock recovery
c) Deadlock detection
d) All of the mentioned
Answer-d
75. When transaction Ti requests a data item currently held by Tj , Ti is allowed to wait only if it has a timestamp smaller than that of Tj (that is, Ti is older than Tj ). Otherwise, Ti is rolled back (dies). This is
a) Wait-die
b) Wait-wound
c) Wound-wait
d) Wait
Answer-a
76. When transaction Ti requests a data item currently held by Tj , Ti is allowed to wait only if it has a timestamp larger than that of Tj (that is, Ti is younger than Tj ). Otherwise, Tj is rolled back (Tj is wounded by Ti ). This is
a) Wait-die
b) Wait-wound
c) Wound-wait
d) Wait
Answer-c
77. The situation where the lock waits only for a specified amount of time for another lock to be released is
a) Lock timeout
b) Wait-wound
c) Timeout
d) Wait
Answer-a
78. The deadlock in a set of transaction can be determined by
a) Read-only graph
b) Wait graph
c) Wait-for graph
d) All of the mentioned
Answer-a
79. A deadlock exists in the system if and only if the wait-for graph contains a ___________.
a) Cycle
b) Direction
c) Bi-direction
d) Rotation
Answer-a
80. Selecting the victim to be rollbacked to the previous state is determined by the minimum cost. The factors determining cost of rollback is
a) How long the transaction has computed, and how much longer the transaction will compute before it completes its designated task.
b) How many data items the transaction has used.
c) How many more data items the transaction needs for it to complete.
d) How many transactions will be involved in the rollback.
e) All of the mentioned.
Answer-e
81. __________ rollback requires the system to maintain additional information about the state of all the running transactions.
a) Total
b) Partial
c) Time
d) Commit
Answer-b
82. Consider relation R(A,B,C,D,E) with functional dependencies:
D -> C, CE -> A, D - >A, AE -> D
Which of the following is a key?
a) A
b) BDE 
c) CDE 
d) CE
Answer-b
83. Let relation R (A,B,C,D,E) satisfy the following functional dependencies:
AB ->C, BC ->D, CD ->E, DE ->A, AE ->B
Which of the following FDs is also guaranteed to be satisfied by R?
a) AC ->B 
b) AC -> D 
c) BCD -> A 
d) BD -> E
Answer-c
84. The concept which checks the syntax of query whether is written according to the rules of grammar is classified as
  a) Query graph
  b) Query tree
  c) Scanner
  d) Parser
Answer-d
85. The processor used to run the code of the queries of interpreted mode or compiled mode is classified as
    a) Runtime database processor
    b) Query optimization processor
    c) Parser runtime processor
    d) Query graphic processor
Answer a
86. The procedure of choosing a suitable query out of all the queries is classified as
    a) Query optimization
    b) Parser optimization
    c) Processing optimization
    d) All of above
Answer d
87. The representation of the query in the form of data structure is classified as
    a) Query graph
    b) Query tree
    c) Scanner tree
    d) Parser tree
Answer B
88. The hashing technique which allocates fixed number of buckets is classified as
   a) Dynamic hashing
   b) Static hashing
   c) External hashing
   d) Internal hashing
Answer C
89. Distributed database has which of the following advantages over a centralized database?
A. Software cost
B. Software complexity
C. Slow Response
D. Modular growth
Answer-d
90. An autonomous homogenous environment is which of the following?
A. The same DBMS is at each node and each DBMS works independently.
B. The same DBMS is at each node and a central DBMS coordinates database access.
C. A different DBMS is at each node and each DBMS works independently.
D. A different DBMS is at each node and a central DBMS coordinates database access.
Answer-a
91. A transaction manager is which of the following?
A. Maintains a log of transactions
B. Maintains before and after database images
C. Maintains appropriate concurrency control
D. All of the above.
Answer-d
92. Location transparency allows for which of the following?
A. Users to treat the data as if it is at one location
B. Programmers to treat the data as if it is at one location
C. Managers to treat the data as if it is at one location
D. All of the above.
Answer- D
93. A heterogeneous distributed database is which of the following?
A. The same DBMS is used at each location and data are not distributed across all nodes.
B. The same DBMS is used at each location and data are distributed across all nodes.
C. A different DBMS is used at each location and data are not distributed across all nodes.
D. A different DBMS is used at each location and data are distributed across all nodes.
Answer-d
94. Some of the columns of a relation are at different sites is which of the following?
A. Data Replication
B. Horizontal Partitioning
C. Vertical Partitioning
D. Horizontal and Vertical Partitioning
Answer-c
95. Which of the following is true concerning a global transaction?
A. The required data are at one local site and the distributed DBMS routes requests as necessary.
B. The required data are located in at least one nonlocal site and the distributed DBMS routes requests as necessary.
C. The required data are at one local site and the distributed DBMS passes the request to only the local DBMS.
D. The required data are located in at least one nonlocal site and the distributed DBMS passes the request to only the local DBMS.
Answer-b
96. A homogenous distributed database is which of the following?
A. The same DBMS is used at each location and data are not distributed across all nodes.
B. The same DBMS is used at each location and data are distributed across all nodes.
C. A different DBMS is used at each location and data are not distributed across all nodes.
D. A different DBMS is used at each location and data are distributed across all nodes.
Answer-b
97. Replication should be used when which of the following exist?
A. When transmission speeds and capacity in a network prohibit frequent refreshing of large tables.
B. When using many nodes with different operating systems and DBMSs and database designs.
C. The application's data can be somewhat out-of-date.
D. All of the above.
Answer-c
98. Storing a separate copy of the database at multiple locations is which of the following?
A. Data Replication
B. Horizontal Partitioning
C. Vertical Partitioning
D. Horizontal and Vertical Partitioning
Answer-a
99. A distributed database is which of the following?
A. A single logical database that is spread to multiple locations and is interconnected by a network
B. A loose collection of file that is spread to multiple locations and is interconnected by a network
C. A single logical database that is limited to one location.
D. A loose collection of file that is limited to one location.
Answer-a
100. A semi join is which of the following?
A. Only the joining attributes are sent from one site to another and then all of the rows are returned.
B. All of the attributes are sent from one site to another and then only the required rows are returned.
C. Only the joining attributes are sent from one site to another and then only the required rows are returned.
D. All of the attributes are sent from one site to another and then only the required rows are returned.
Answer-c
101. Which of the following is a disadvantage of replication?
A. Reduced network traffic
B. If the database fails at one site, a copy can be located at another site.
C. Each site must have the same storage capacity.
D. Each transaction may proceed without coordination across the network.
Answer-c
102. A distributed database can use which of the following strategies?
A. Totally centralized at one location and accessed by many sites
B. Partially or totally replicated across sites
C. Partitioned into segments at different sites
D. All of the above
Answer-d
103. Which of the following is not one of the stages in the evolution of distributed DBMS?
A. Unit of work
B. Remote unit of work
C. Distributed unit of Work
D. Distributed request
Answer-a
104. The nested transaction model that requires the commit process to occur in a bottom-up fashion through the top-level transaction is more precisely called a_________
a) open nested transaction.
b) closed nested transaction.
c) both a and b
d) none of these
ans:b)closed nested transaction.
105. Which transaction does not enforce atomicity at the top level?
a) open nested transaction
b) closed nested transaction
c) both a and b
d) none of these
ans:a)open nested transaction
106. A specialization of the open nested transaction where the tree of sub transactions is balanced is called__________
a) closed nested transaction
b) multilevel transaction
c) both a and b
d) none
ans:b)multilevel transaction
107. _______ is a multilevel long-duration transaction.
a)nested transaction
b)Saga
c)both a and b
d)multilevel transaction
Ans:b)Saga

108. A _________ is an activity involving the coordinated execution of multiple tasks performed by different processing entities, which may be people or software systems, such as a DBMS, an  application program, or an electronic mail system.
a)workflow
b)nested transaction
c)both a and b
d)none
ans:a)workflow
109. The general problems involved in workflow systems:
a) the specification of the workflow
b) the execution of the workflow
c)both a and b
d)none
ans:c)both a and b
110. The ECA model stands for:
a)Effect-Cause-Action model
b)Event-Condition-Action model
c)Element-Cause-Action model
d)none
ans:b)event-condition-action model

111. Designing a generic  is  a very complex task
a)real-time database
b)image and multimedia database
c)database
d)all of these
 ans:a)real-time database
        
112.Hard real time database has:
a)no time constraint
b)strict time constraint
c)less time constraint
d)none
ans:b)strict time costraint

113. The ideal real-time database should be able to perform________
a)real-time ACID transactions
b)nested transaction
c)closed nested transaction
d)none
ans:a)real-time ACID transactions

114. A real-time database should be evaluated based on the support for __________
a)TACID transactions
b)ACID transactions
c)both
d)none
ans:a)TACID transactions

115. At the heart of__________  lies the multimedia database management system
a)multimedia information systems
b)security information systems
c)distributed database
d)all of these
ans:a)multimedia information systems

116. Traditionally, a______  consists of a controlled collection of data related to a given entity.
a)database
b)DBMS
c)RDBMS
d)none
ans:a)database

117. __________ is a collection of interrelated data with the set of Programs used to define, create, store, access, manage, and query the database
a) DBMS
b)RDBMS
c)database
d)none
ans:a)DBMS

118. We can view a_______  as a controlled collection of multimedia data items, such as text, images, graphic objects, sketches, video, and audio.
a)multimedia database
b)multimedia DBMS
c)both a and b
d)none
ans:a)multimedia database
119. ____________ ensures that data items need not be duplicated during different program invocations requiring the data.
a)Integration
b)persistence
c)consistency
d)none
ans:a)Integration

120.___________ ensures multimedia database consistency through rules, which usually impose some form of execution order on concurrent transactions.
a)Concurrency control.
b)integration
c)both a and b
d)integrity control
ans:a)concurrency control

121._____________ restricts unauthorized access and modification 
of stored data
a)Privacy.
b)integrity control
c)concurrency
d)none
ans:a)privacy

122._______ ensures consistency of the database state from one transaction to another through constraints imposed on transaction
a)Integrity control.
b)privacy
c)concurrency
d)none
ans:a)integrity control

123.__________means methods needed to ensure that results of transactions that fail do not affect the persistent data storage.
a)Recovery
b)privacy
c)version control
d)query support
ans:a)recovery

124._______ ensures that the query mechanisms are suited for multimedia data
a)Version control
b)Query support. 
c)integrity
none
ans:b)Query support

125. Organization and management of different versions of persistent objects, which might be required by applications is called___________.
a)Version control.
b)query support
c)integrity 
d)none
ans:a)version control

126. How many layers are there in the Dexter model?
a)5
b)3
c)2
d)7
ans:b)3

127.Dexter model consists of :
a) Run-time Layer
b)Storage Layer
c)Within-Component Layer
d)all of the above
ans:d)all of the above

128. The_______  offers the mechanism for addressing the link sources and targets even inside of the components (Span-to-
Span-Links).
a)Anchoring
b)run-time layer
c)link method
d)all of these
ans:a)Anchoring

129. The __________ offers a possibility to deposit information on the display of components in the Storage Layer by the Run-Time-Layer.
a)Presentation Specification
b)Anchoring
c)system specification
d)none
ans:a)Presentation Specification

130.______ describes the hypertext structure as a finite set of components and a set of two access functions: resolver- and accessor- function
a)Storage layer
b)link layer
c)run-time layer
d)application layer
ans:a)Storage layer

131.___________ is considered as a "node", that means as a primitive, it's substructure and content are specified in the Within-Component Layer.
a)atom
b)unit
c)element
d)all of the above
ans:a)atom
132. __________ is a hierarchical structuring of'components
a)Composite Component
b)elementary component
c)tree
d)none
ans:a)Composite Component

133. The two access functions on components are
a)accessor-function
b)resolver-function
c)recovery function
d)both a and b
e)both a and c
ans:d)both a and b

134. Media objects are modeled from two perspectives - the first describing the_______  of the object, the second giving its _________ meaning
a)context,semantic
b)job,syntactic
c)costructor,mathematical
d)none
ans:a)context,semantic

135. Increasingly, organizations need to extend their administrative (relational) databases with to represent text documents, images, 
charts, audio, or video.
a)meta data
b) media data
c)multimedia data
d)none
ans:b) media data

136.Which database consists of a combination of media data types and 'traditional' structured data ?
a)Traditional database
b)multimedia database
c)both a and b
d)none
ans:b)multimedia database

137. A text document can be described from:
a) Semantic content of the document, i.e. representation of its meaning,
b) Context of the document, e.g. its author, publisher
c)Structure of the document, e.g. its language, style, length
d)all of the above
ans:d)all of the above

138Automatic modeling of the semantic content of a document 
collection is based on 
a) Heaps' law of vocabulary growth 
b) Zipf's law of term distribution
c)both a and b
d)none
ans:c)both a and b

139.___________ states that there will be a near finite vocabulary for a set of documents that can be used to describe the semantic content of the documents in a document collection.
a)Heaps' law
b)Zipf's law
c)all of the above
d)none
ans: a)Heaps' law

140.__________ states that the vocabulary is unequally distributed
a)Zipf's law
b)Heaps' law
c)both a and b
d)none

1401.The index terms can be selected from a domain_________. 
a)taxonomy or ontology.
b)anatomy
c)vocabulary
d)all of these
ans:a)taxonomy or ontology

142. Structural features, also called _________
a) low level features
b)high level features
c)middle level features
d)none
ans:a) low level features

143. A__________ database is a database that can be queried and/or updated through the World Wide Web (WWW).
a)web
b)deep web
c)surface web
d)none
ans:a)web 

144. The hidden information inside the web database sources is 
called the__________. 
a)deep web
b)surface web
c)both a and b
d)none
ans:a)deep web

145. Which of the following is easily accessed by traditional search engines?
a)surface web
b)deep web
c)web
d)none
ans:a)surface web

146.___________ was developed by Microsoft as a standard access method to different databases.
a)Open DataBase Connectivity (ODBC)
b)JDBC
c)both a and b
d)none
ans:a)Open DataBase Connectivity (ODBC)

147. The ODBC interface defines:
a) A standard way to connect and log on to a DBMS.
b) A standardized representation for data types.
c) Libraries of ODBC API function calls that allow an application to connect to a DBMS, execute SQL statements, and retrieve results.
d)all of the above
ans:d)all of the above

148. The ODBC standard defines conformance levels for drivers in areas of :
a) ODBC API 
b) ODBC SQL grammar
c)JDBC
d)both a and b
ans:d)both a and b

149. The three ODBC API conformance levels are:
a)Core, Level 1 and Level 2.
b)level 0,level 1,level 2
c)level 0,core,level 1
d)none
ans:a)Core, Level 1 and Level 2.

150.___________ are drivers that provide JDBC access via ODBC drivers, which is widely used by developers to connect to databases in a non-Java environment.
a)JDBC-ODBC bridges
b)ODBC-JDBC bridges
c)JVM
d)none
ans:a)JDBC-ODBC bridges

151. A web database environment contains:
a)a web browser (the client), 
b)a web server (understands HTTP) 
c) the DBMS (understands SQL)
d)all of the above
ans:d)all of the above

152. Database-to-Web connectivity technologies are either
a) two-tier or three-tier technologies
b)three-tier or four-tier technologies
c)all of the above
d)none
ans:a) two-tier or three-tier technologies
153._________ is a program that runs on the server tier and is responsible for all the transformations between HTTP and SQL
a)CGI
b)SSI
c)JAVA Applets
d)none
ans:a)CGI

154._______are java programs that can be dynamically loaded by the browser and executed in the client site.
a)Java applets
b)SSI
c)CGI
d)none
ans:a)JAVA applets

155._______is a code that is written inside an HTML page and is processed by the web server.
a)SSI 
b)CGI
c)JAVA Applets
d)none
ans:a)SSI 
156.___________gave a significant boost to web-based and business-to-business (B2B) applications.
a)XML
b)HTML
c) SGML
d)none
ans:a)XML

157. Full form of SGML is:
a) Standard Generalized Markup Language
b)Standardised General Markup Language
c)both a and b is correct
d)none
ans:a) Standard Generalized Markup Language

158. A database that has an added XML mapping layer provided either by the database vendor or a third party is called:
a)XML Enabled Database (XEDB)
b)Hybrid XML Databases
c)SSI
d)none
ans:a)XML Enabled Database (XEDB)

159. A database that can be treated as either a Native XML Database or Relational-to-XML schema mapping is:
a)Hybrid XML Databases (HXD)
b)SSI
c)XML Enabled Database (XEDB)
d)none
ans:a)Hybrid XML Databases (HXD)

160. A_________ of storage is the smallest grouping of data that is logically held together in storage.
a)fundamental unit
b)single group
c)singleton
d)none
ans: a)fundamental unit

161. From a relational database perspective, the fundamental unit of storage is a __________
a)tuple
b)degree
c)cardinality
d)none
ans:a)tuple

162. From a native XML database perspective, the fundamental unit of storage is a ___________
a)document
b)file
c)database
d)record
ans:a)document

163. Both table-based mapping and object-relational mappings define :
a)bi-directional mappings
b)one-to-many relation
c)both a and b
d)none
ans.a)bi-directional mappings
164. ______ is a collection of facts, such as values or measurements.
 A. Data
 B. information
 C. things
 D. items
 ANSWER: A
165. A______ is a collection of related files that are usually integrated, linked or cross-referenced to one another.
 A. data
 B. information
 C. database
 D. datafield
 ANSWER: C
166. A _________ is a set of software programs that allows users to create, edit and update data in database files, and store and retrieve data from those database
files.
 A. data base
 B. data management system
 C. database management system
 D. office management system
 ANSWER: C
167. Data in a database can be added, deleted, changed, sorted or searched all using a _________.
 A. DBMS
 B. SQL
 C. C++
 D. Java
 ANSWER: A
168. DBMS stands for ______________.
 A. Database associated
 B. Database administrator
 C. Database application
 D. Database management system
 ANSWER: D
169. ____________ is a place where data can be stored in a structured manner.
 A. CPU
 B. Database
 C. ALU
 D. Memory
 ANSWER: B
170. A database is a complex ______.
 A. Data structure
 B. Memory
 C. Both
 D. None
 ANSWER: A
171. ____________is a collection of programs performing all necessary action associated with a database.
 A. Database associated
 B. Database administrator
 C. Database application
 D. Database management system
 ANSWER: D
172. ________is a collection of application programs that interacts with the database along with DBMS.
 A. A database system
 B. A database application
 C. Database administration
 D. Data system
 ANSWER: A
173. A _____view of data expresses the way a user thinks about data.
 A. Logical view
 B. Physical view
 C. Both
 D. None
 ANSWER: A
174. A transaction completes its execution is said to be _______.
 A. High level
 B. committed
 C. Medium level
 D. rollback
 ANSWER: B
175. The overall description of a database is called______.
 A. Data definition
 B. Data manipulation
 C. Data integrity
 D. Database schema
 ANSWER: D
176. Which languages are used to define and query a database?
 A. Database
 B. Memory
 C. Metadata
 D. All of these
 ANSWER: A
177. DDL stand for _________.
 A. Data definition language
 B. Data description languages
 C. Data design languages
 D. Database dictionary languages
 ANSWER: A
178. DML stands for _________.
 A. Data description languages
 B. Data design languages
 C. Database dictionary languages
 D. Data manipulation languages
 ANSWER: D
179. Which is used for data retrieval from the database?
 A. DDL
 B. DML
 C. SDL
 D. VDL
 ANSWER: B
180. Data are stored in________ as database.
 A. Data files
 B. Data dictionary
 C. Database
 D. Data administrator
 ANSWER: A
181. Which sql query is used to remove the table and all its data?
 A. Drop table
 B. Remove table
 C. Alter table
 D. Quit table
 ANSWER: A
182. Which is the person responsible for overall control of the database system?
 A. DDL
 B. DBMS
 C. DBA
 D. SDL
 ANSWER: C
183. Retrieval of data is done by using a ____.
 A. Stack
 B. Query
 C. Linked list
 D. All of these
 ANSWER: B
184. DML is a languages by which user accesses or manipulates the ________.
 A. Data model
 B. Data consistency
 C. Data integration
 D. Data sharing
 ANSWER: A
185. Which is installs, configures, troubleshoots and maintains a database system?
 A. DBA
 B. DDL
 C. DML
 D. SDL
 ANSWER: A
186. SQL stands for ____________.
 A. System query language
 B. Structured query language
 C. Sets query languages
 D. None of these
 ANSWER: B
187. Which of the following refers to the collection of related data values or items called fields?
 A. Record
 B. Record blocking
 C. Fixed-length record
 D. Variable-length record
 ANSWER: A
188. In SQL, the __________ command(s) is (are) used to create an index for a table or cluster.
 A. CREATE INDEX
 B. SET INDEX TO FILE
 C. MODIFY INDEX
 D. All of the above
 ANSWER: A
189. In SQL, which of the following is not a data definition language commands?
 A. RENAME
 B. REVOKE
 C. GRANT
 D. UPDATE
 ANSWER: D
190. A field used to identify a record is called as a ____________.
 A. key
 B. column
 C. pointer
 D. index
 ANSWER: A
191. A field that can identify a record uniquely is called as _________ of the record.
 A. foreign key
 B. super key
 C. primary key
 D. candidate key
 ANSWER: C
192. ______________ means multiple copies of the same data items.
 A. Data reduction
 B. Data integrity
 C. Data consistency
 D. Data redundancy
 ANSWER: D
193. The _____________ suffers from the possibility of lack of data consistency.
 A. file management system
 B. database management systems
 C. relational database management systems
 D. object oriented relational database management systems.
 ANSWER: A
194. The __________ knows the details of the data storage.
 A. decision support system analyst.
 B. database administrator
 C. database manger
 D. transaction manger
 ANSWER: B
195. In _____________, one or more users/programs attempt to access the same data at the same time.
 A. concurrency.
 B. transaction control.
 C. locking
 D. two phase locking
 ANSWER: A
196. The _______________ employs parent-child relationships as well as child parent relationships.
 A. hierarchical databases
 B. network databases.
 C. relation databases
 D. databases
 ANSWER: B
197. The file in DBMS is called as _________ in RDBMS.
 A. console
 B. schema.
 C. table.
 D. objects.
 ANSWER: C
198. ___________ can be used to retrieve data from multiple tables.
 A. Embedded SQL
 B. Dynamic SQL
 C. Joins
 D. Views
 ANSWER: C
199. The _____________ of a database presents the view that the end users have.
 A. conceptual view
 B. external view
 C. internal view
 D. non conceptual view
 ANSWER: B
200. Internal view provides information regarding the _______________.
 A. database
 B. organization of the database.
 C. data without technology
 D. data with integrity
 ANSWER: B
201. A__________ is a three dimensional view of data.
 A. form
 B. database.
 C. table
 D. query
 ANSWER: B
202. Commit and rollback are related to ______________.
 A. data integrity
 B. data consistency
 C. data sharing
 D. data security
 ANSWER: B
203. Data is processed using _____________.
 A. data definition language
 B. data manipulation language
 C. data control language
 D. transaction control language
 ANSWER: B
204. In ___________, we have a strict parent-child relationship only.
 A. hierarchical databases
 B. network databases
 C. object oriented databases
 D. relational databases
 ANSWER: A
205. The ____________ refers to the way data is organized in and accessible from DBMS.
 A. database hierarchy
 B. data organization
 C. data sharing
 D. data model
 ANSWER: D
206. _____________ introduced the relational databases.
 A. Atul Kahate.
 B. James Gossling.
 C. EF Codd.
 D. Dennies Rithchie.
 ANSWER: C
207. Row is synonymous with the term ____________.
 A. record.
 B. relation
 C. column
 D. field
 ANSWER: A
208. A relation is considered as _______________.
 A. column
 B. one-dimensional table
 C. two-dimensional table
 D. three-dimensional table
 ANSWER: C
209. An attribute is a(n) ___________________.
 A. column of a table
 B. two-dimensional table.
 C. row of a table.
 D. key of a table
 ANSWER: A
210. What process indicates the end of a transaction?
 A. only when it is committed
 B. only when it is rollbacked
 C. when it is committed or rollbacked
 D. when it is committed and rollbacked
 ANSWER: C
211. A Transaction ends ________________.
 A. only when it is Committed.
 B. only when it is Rolledback
 C. when it is Committed or Rolledback
 D. only when it is initialized
 ANSWER: C
212. _______ keyword is used to eliminate the duplicates.
 A. distinct
 B. unique
 C. union
 D. intersect
 ANSWER: A
213. ____________ keyword is used to find the number of values in a column.
 A. TOTAL
 B. COUNT
 C. ADD
 D. SUM
 ANSWER: B
214. _____________ keyword is used to find the sum of values in a column.
 A. TOTAL
 B. COUNT
 C. ADD
 D. SUM
 ANSWER: D
215. Which of the following is not an RDBMS?
 A. Ms Access.
 B. Oracle 8i.
 C. Ms Sql Server.
 D. Informix.
 ANSWER: A
216. _____________ command can be used to modify a column in a table.
 A. alter
 B. update
 C. set
 D. create
 ANSWER: A
217. In SQL, which command(s) is(are) used to change a table's storage characteristics?
 A. ALTER TABLE
 B. MODIFY TABLE
 C. CHANGE TABLE
 D. All of the above
 ANSWER: A
218. In SQL, which of the following is not a data definition language commands?
 A. RENAME
 B. REVOKE
 C. GRANT
 D. UPDATE
 ANSWER: D
219. In SQL, which command is used to select only one copy of each set of duplicate rows?
 A. SELECT DISTINCT
 B. SELECT UNIQUE
 C. SELECT DIFFERENT
 D. All of the above
 ANSWER: A
220. Data Mining used now a days for-
a) The data is abundant and being warehoused.
b) The computing power is affordable.
c) The competitive pressure is strong.
d) All of the above
Answer-d
221. Data Mining means-
a) Exploratory data analysis
b) Data driven discovery
c) Deductive learning
d) All of above
Answer-d
222. KDD means-
a) Uses known data to forecast future trends, events, etc.
b) Concrete information gleaned from known data.  
c) Simple grouping and partitioning of data to infer new information.
d) Entire process of applying computer-based methodology
Answer-b
223. Metadata is data that describes other data, Can describe an individual element, or a collection of elements. 
a) False
b) True
Answer-b
224. Database perspective on data mining is-
a) Scalability & ease to use
b) Real  world data
c) New updates
d) All of these
Answer-d
225. Association rule R : itemset1=>itemset2 itemset1,2 are disjoint and itemset2 is non-empty then it means-
a) If transaction includes Itemset1  then it also has Itemset2.
b) If transaction includes Itemset1  then it must not include Itemset2.
c) If transaction includes Itemset2  then it must not include Itemset1.
d) Transaction neither include itemset1 nor itemset2.
Answer-a
226. Output of Data Mining Processing is-
a) Not a subset of database
b) Subset of database
c) Precise output will given
d) None of the above
Answer-a
227. 'Association rules focused on one target field'-this statement is-
a) True
b) False
Answer-a
228. Which statement is not correct-
a) Classification is the process of predicting the class of a new item.
b) Data warehouse is allows for easier query development as a single repository can be queried.
c) Regression deals with the description of a value, rather than a class.
d) Data obtained through Data Mining is incredibly valuable.
Answer-c
229. In Data Mining processing query should be
a) SQL
b) Poorly defined
c) Well defined
d) Precised language
answer-b
230. Proper example of association rules of Data Mining is(for query)-
a) Find all credit applicants who are poor credit risks.
b) Identify customers with similar buying habits.
c) Find all items which are frequently purchased with some particular item. 
d) All of these
Answer-c
231. Descriptive data mining model is based on-
a) Association & Classification 
b) Regression & summerization
c) Summerization & association
d) Regression & prediction
 Answer-c
232. Clustering task is basically-
a) Real valued prediction
b) Unsupervised learning
c) Supervised learning
d) Pattern recognition
Answer-b
233. To genarate strong association rules it will must satisfy-
a) Max support & max confidence
b) Min support & max confidence
c) Min support & min confidence
d) Max support & min confidence
Answer-c
234. If a association rule is like X(P:Customer,W)^Y(P,Q)=>Buys(P,R) then which statement is correct?
1)P & R are acted as predicate variables
2) W,Q,R are acted as object variables
3) P & Q are acted as predicate variables
4) P,R,W are acted as object variables
Answer-2
235. Data Mining means-
a) archives information gathered from multiple sources, and stores it under a unified schema, at a single site.
b) seeks to discover knowledge automatically in the form of statistical rules and patterns from large databases.
c) Corporate decision making requires a unified view of all organizational data, including historical data
d) None of the above
Answer-b
236. In association rules Support is-
a) Measure of what fraction of the population satisfies both the antecedent and the consequent of the rule.
b) Measure of how often the consequent is true when the antecedent is true. 
c) Co-occurrence is higher than predicted.
d) None of these.
Answer-a
237. OLTP is-
a) On-Line Transactive Processing  
b) On-Live Transaction Processing  
c) On-Line Transitive Processing  
d) On-Line Transaction Processing 
Answer-d
238. In association rules Confidence is-
a) Co-occurrence is lowerer than predicted.
b) Mmeasure of what fraction of the population satisfies both the antecedent and the consequent of the rule.
c) Measure of how often the consequent is true when the antecedent is true. 
d) None of these.
Answer-c
240. which statement is not true-
a) Data warehouse used to run business.
b) OLTP is application oriented.
c) Data warehouse is subject oriented.
d) OLTP used isolated data.
Answer-a
241. Can discrimination be based on features like sex, age, national origin?
a) Yes
b) No
Answer-a
242. Data Warehouse is basically-
a) Copy sources into a single DB and try to keep it up-to-date.
b) A decision support DB maintained separately from the organization’s operational database
c) Frequently essential for analytic queries.
d) All of these
Answer-d
243. Which statement is true-
a) Databases at store branches handle OLAP.
b) In OLAP queries do not depend on having an absolutely up-to-date database.
c) Relational OLAP(ROLAP) used a data model called data-cube.
d) Multidimensional OLAP(MOLAP) used a data model called star-schema.
Answer-b

244. 'Training set means a data sample in which the classification is already known.' this statement is-
a) True
b) False
Answer-a
245. Data Mining is important for-
a) Rapid computerization of businesses produce huge amount of data
b) How to make best use of data?
c) A growing realization: knowledge discovered from data can be used for competitive advantage.
d) All of the above.
Answer-d


246. Software that defines a database, stores the data, supports a query language, produces reports and creates data entry screens is a:
A) data dictionary 
B) database management system (DBMS)   
C) decision support system   
D) relational database 
Ans: B
247. The modern database report writer: 
A) is a career path that focuses on creating, managing and supporting the reports generated from databases   
B) provide limited control over how information is displayed and reported.   
C) provides the tools for database designer to display information in the desired format   
D)provides the tools for the database administrator to monitor and report on database use and activity 
Ans: C
248. The separation of the data definition from the program is known as: 
A) data dictionary   
B) data independence   
C) data integrity   
D) referential integrity 
Ans: B
249. In the client / server model, the database:
A) is downloaded to the client upon request   
B) is shared by both the client and server   
C) resides on the client side   
D) resides on the server side 
Ans: D
250. The traditional storage of data that is organized by customer, stored in separate folders in filing cabinets is an example of what type of 'database' system? 
A) Hierarchical   
B) Network   	
C) Object oriented   
D) Relational 
Ans: A
251. The database design that consists of multiple tables that are linked together through matching data stored in each table is called a:
A) Hierarchical database   
B) Network database   
C) Object oriented database   
D) Relational database 
Ans: D
252. What is the main limitation of Hierarchical Databases? 
A) Limited capacity (unable to hold much data)    
B) Limited flexibility in accessing data   
C) Overhead associated with maintaining indexes   
D) The performance of the database is poor 
Ans: B
253. An abstract data type is used to:
A) link data from remote databases   
B) prevent users from getting to database security information   
C) provide a conceptual view of the data so it is easier to understand   
D) store complex data structure to represent the properties of objects 
Ans: D
254. One of the first phases of a new database project that involves critical areas, expensive hardware or software within the organization is called ___________. 
A) analysis phase   
B) feasibility study   
C) investigation stage   
D) system design 
Ans: B
255. Which component of the database management system (DBMS) most affects the ability to handle large problems (scalability)? 
A) Data Storage Subsystem  
B) Database Engine   
C) Query Processor   
D) Security Subsystem 
Ans: B
256. The primary difference between the Relational database (RDB) and Object Oriented database (OODB) models is: 
A) OODB incorporates methods in with the definition of the data structure, while RDB does not   
B) OODB supports multiple objects in the same database while RDB only supports a single table per database   
C) RDB allows the definition of the relationships between the different tables, while OODB does not allow the relationships to be defined between objects   
D) RDB supports indexes, while OODB does not support indexes 
Ans: A
257. Which of the following items is not the advantage of a DBMS? 
A) Improved ability to enforce standards   
B) Improved data consistency   
C) Local control over the data   
D) Minimal data redundancy 
Ans: C
13. The predominant way of storing data today is using which type of database models? 
A) Hierarchical   
B) Network   
C) Object oriented   
D) Relational  
Ans: D
258. Two different terms are used to describe the characteristics of interest for an entity. They are attributes and:
A) classes   
B) entities   
C) properties   
D) traits 
Ans: C
259. When building a database, the data dealing with an entity is modeled as a:
A) attribute   
B) class   
C) object   
D) table 
Ans: B
260. Database system modelers use this type of diagram to graphically represent both the data structure and how the different objects are interrelated. 
A) Class Diagram   
B) Data Diagram   
C) Object Diagram   
D) Table Relationship Diagram 
Ans: A
261. In relational database model, after conceptually designing your database, the information contained in a single class would be stored in a:
A) database   
B) field   
C) property   
D) table 
Ans: D
262. The property (or set of properties) that uniquely defines each row in a table is called the:
A) identifier   
B) index   
C) primary key   
D) symmetric key 
Ans: C
263. Business rules can be represented in the database through:
A) associations (or relationships)   
B) attributes   
C) properties   
D) secondary keys 
Ans:A
264. The association role defines: 
A) how tables are related in the database   
B) the relationship between the class diagram and the tables in the database   
C) the tables that each attribute is contained   
D) which attribute is the table's primary key 
Ans: 
265. A composition association is drawn using which symbol:
A) A line which loops back onto the same table   
B) Small closed diamond at the end of a line connecting two tables   
C) Small open diamond at the end of a line connecting two tables   
D) Small triangle at the end of a line connecting the aggregated item and multiple component items 
Ans: B
266. A reflexive association is drawn using which symbol:
A) a line which loops back onto the same table   
B) small closed diamond at the end of a line connecting two tables   
C) small open diamond at the end of a line connecting two tables   
D) small triangle at the end of a line connecting the aggregated item and multiple component items 
Ans:A

267. What is the most appropriate special association that indicates that multiple textbooks make up a course required reading list? 
A) aggregation association   
B) generalization association   
C) n-ary association   
D) reflexive association 
Ans: C
268. What is the special association that indicates that one object can be broken down into multiple special cases? 
A) composition association   
B) generalization association   
C) n-ary association   
D) reflexive association 
Ans: B
269 The ability to define common properties or functions in the higher class and then modify them in the lower classes is called:
A) Inheritance   
B) Polymorphism   
C) Reflexive   
D) Transformance 
Ans: B
270. A reflexive association is one where one class is:
A) broken down into special cases   
B) combined with multiple other classes   
C) combined with one other class   
D) linked back to itself 
Ans:D
271. Which of the following statements is not correct?
A) A primary goal of a database system is to share data with multiple users   
B) It is possible to change a method or property inherited from a higher level class   
C) While companies collect data all the time, the structure of the data changes very often.   
D) In a client / server environment, data independence causes client side applications to be essentially independent of the database stored on the server side.
Ans: C 
272. Which of the following statements is not correct?
A) Data Normalization is the process of defining the table structure   
B) The purpose of class diagrams is to model the interrelationships between the different classes in the database   
C) Individual objects are stored as rows in a table   
D) Properties of an object are stored as columns in a table. 
Ans: A
273. Which of the following statements is not correct?
A) The primary key must be unique for a given table   
B) Specifying a zero (0) for the lower bound for the association multiplicity on a class diagram indicates that the item is required   
C) Specifying a one (1) for the lower bound for the association multiplicity on a class diagram indicates that the item is required   
D) Most databases allow multiple records that are identical (i.e., records that have the same values for all properties).
Ans: B
274. Which of the following statements is not correct?
A) All many-to-many relationships must be converted to a set of one-to-many relationships by adding a new entity   
B) In a one-to-one relationship between two classes, the two classes are generally described by one table in relational database model   
C) Encapsulation provides some security and control features   
D) Propertiesand functions can be protected from other areas of the applications
Ans:B
275. The procedure of choosing a suitable query out of all the queries is classified as
a) query optimization
b) parser optimization
c) processing optimization
d) all of above
ans-d
276.The representation of the query in the form of data structure is classified as
a) query graph
b) query tree
c) scanner tree
d) parser tree
Answer B
277.In sort merge strategy, the small sub files sorted are called
a) runs
b) folders
c) blocks
d) indexes
Answer A
278. The processor used to run the code of the queries of interpreted mode or compiled mode is classified as
a) runtime database processor
b) query optimization processor
c) parser runtime processor
d) query graphic processor
Answer A
279. The representation of the query in the form of data structure is classified as
a) query graph
b) query tree
c) scanner tree
d) parser tree
Answer B
280.. ............. is a special type of stored procedure that is automatically invoked whenever the data in the table is modified.
A) Procedure
B) Trigger
C) Curser
D) None of the above
ans-b)triger
281.Some of the utilities of DBMS are .............
i) Loading          
ii) Backup               
iii) File organization          
iv) Process Organization
A) i, ii, and iv only
B) i, ii and iii only
C) ii, iii and iv only
D) All i, ii, iii, and iv
ans-b
282 .............. is a combination of two of more attributes used as a primary key
A) Composite Key
B) Alternate Key
C) Candidate Key
D) Foreign Key
ans-a
 283. DBMS is a collection of ………….. that enables user to create and maintain a database.
A) Keys
B) Translators
C) Program
D) Language Activity
ans-c
 284. In a relational schema, each tuple is divided into fields called 
A) Relations
B) Domains
C) Queries
D) All of the above
ans-b
285. In an ER model, ……………. is described in the database by storing its data.
A) Entity
B) Attribute
C) Relationship
D) Notation
ans-a
286. DFD stands for
A) Data Flow Document
B) Data File Diagram
C) Data Flow Diagram
D) Non of the above
ans-c
287. A top-to-bottom relationship among the items in a database is established by a 
A) Hierarchical schema
B) Network schema
C) Relational Schema
D) All of the above
ans-a
 288. A logical schema 
A) is the entire database
B) is a standard way of organizing information into accessible parts.
C) Describes how data is actually stored on disk.
D) All of the above
ans-b
 289. The collection of information stored in a database at a particular moment is called as ......
A. schema
B. instance of the database
C. data domain
D. independence
ans-b
 290. DBMS helps achieve
A. Data independence 
B. Centralized control of data
C. Neither A nor B
D. Both A and B 
ans-d
291 .......... command can be used to modify a column in a table
A. alter
B. update
C. set
D. create
ans-alter
292. Centralizing the integrity checking directly under the DBMS ………….. Duplication and ensures the consistency and validity of the database.
A) Increases
B) Skips
C) Does not reduce
D) Reduces
ans-reduces
293. A set of possible data values is called
A. attribute
B. degree
C. tuple
D. domain
ans-domain
294. A primary key if combined with a foreign key creates
A. Parent-Child relationship between the tables that connect them
B. Many to many relationship between the tables that connect them
C. Network model between the tables that connect them
D. None of the above
ans-a
295. Which two files are used during operation of the DBMS
A. Query languages and utilities
B. DML and query language
C. Data dictionary and transaction log
D. Data dictionary and query language
ans-c
296. A ........... is a set of column that identifies every row in a table.
A. composite key
B. candidate key
C. foreign key
D. super key
ans-super key
297.  ………………. First proposed the process of normalization.
A) Edgar. W
B) Edgar F. Codd
C) Edward Stephen
D) Edward Codd
ans-b
298.  _______refers to the basic facts and entities, such as names and numbers.
a.       Data
b.      Information
c.       Input
d.      Output
Answer-b
299.      Information is processed from __________
a.       Output
b.      Data
c.       Memory
d.      None of these
Answer-c
300.      MIS stands for:
a.       Management Information Server
b.      Management Information Service
c.       Management Information System
d.      Master Information System
ans-c
301.  Which is the false statement:
a.  A database is ordered collection of data.
b.      A database is systematic compilation of records in a computer.
c.       DBMS manages the database
d.      Data helps in making decisions.
ans-d

302.      Which is the data model
a.       Relational
b.      Object-Relational
c.       Network
d.      All of these
ans-d
303.      Which is not the feature of database:
a.      Data redundancy
b.      Independence
c.       Flexibility
d.      Data Integrity
ans-a
304.      Which is the type of data independence:
a.       Physical data independence
b.      Logical data independence
c.       Both
d.      None of these
ans-c
305.      Which is the feature of database:
a.       Query Language
b.      Multi user access
c.       Data Dictionary
d.      All of these
ans-d

306.      Which is the advantage of database:
a.       Prevents Data redundancy
b.      Restricts unauthorized access
c.       Persistent storage
d.      Backup and recovery
e.       Integrity Constraints
f.        All of these
ans-f
307.  Which is the database language:
a.       C
b.      C++
c.       SQL
d.      None of these
ans-sql

308.  Which person is responsible for overall activities for database:
a.       Database designer
b.      Database analyst
c.       Database Administrator
d.      Database manager
ans-c

309.  Which level of database is viewed by user:
a.       Internal level
b.      External Level
c.       Conceptual Level
d.      All of these
ans-b

310.  Internal level has:
a.       Individual Users View of the database
b.      Community view of the database
c.       Physical Representation of the database
d.      All of these
ans-c
311.  Which is the component of database management system:
a.       Query Language
b.      Database Manager
c.       File manager
d.      All of these
ans-d

312.  ______is the structure of the database.
a.       Table
b.      Relation
c.       Schema
d.      None of these
ans-c

313.  Schema is usually stored in____________.
a.       Tables
b.      Data Dictionary
c.       Both
d.      None of these
ans-b
314.  Schema is defined by:
a.       DML
b.      DDL
c.       DCL
d.      DQL
ans-b
315.   DML language is used to:
a.       Define schema
b.      Define internal level
c.       Access Data
d.      All of these
ans-c
316.  DBMS is the bridge between operating system and ___________.
a.       User
b.      Database administrator
c.       Application program
d.      None of these
ans-c

317.  Which is the most popular database model:
a.       Network Model
b.      Relational Model
c.       Hierarchical Model
d.      Object Oriented
ans-b
318.  Which is the schema object:
a.       Database links and clusters
b.      Packages and Indexes
c.       Procedures and functions
d.      All of these
ans-d
319.  In database records are called:
a.       Attributes
b.      Entity
c.       Tuples
d.      Relations
ans-c

320.  An entity has a set of ___________ that describe it.
a.      Attributes
b.      Entity
c.       Tuples
d.      Relations
ans-a
321.  In ER model rectangle represents:
a.       Attributes
b.      Entity set
c.       Relationships
d.      None of these
ans-b
322.  Date is the type of attribute:
a.       Simple
b.      Composite
c.       Single values
d.      Multi valued
ans-b
323.  __________is the attribute or group of attributes that uniquely identify occurrence of each entity.
a.       Foreign key
b.      Super Key
c.       Primary Key
d.      All of these
ans-c

324.   _________is the real world object, such as a person, place etc.
a.       Attribute
b.      Entity
c.       Records
d.      All of these
ans-b
325.  Grant and revoke is the type of command:
a.       DDL
b.      DML
c.       DCL
d.      DQL
ans-c

326.  A user that manages the files of application in DBMS is called:
a.       Administrator
b.      Database analyst
c.       File Manager
d.      None of these
ans-c

327.  ________is the information about data.
a.       Data
b.      Meta-Data
c.       Entity
d.      Relations
ans-b
328.virtual database is uesd to refer ----------- system
a.distributed system
b.mediator system
c.local system
d.none of these
ans.b
329. processes ensures that the distributed databases remain up-to-date and current
a.  replication
b.  consistency
c.  duplication.
d.  a & c both
ans. d

330.Which of the following is not one of the advantages of parallel processing?
a. scaleup
b. autonomy
c. speedup
d.availability
ans. b

331. normalization of database is ued to
a. eliminate redundancy
b. improve security
c. improve efficiency
d.minimize errors
ans.a
332. a relational database which is in 3NFmay still have undesirable data redundancy because there may exit
a.transitive functional dependencies
b. non-trivial functinal dependencies involving prime attributes on the right side
c. non-trivial functinal dependencies involving prime attributes on the left side
d.non-trivial functinal dependencies involving only prime attributes
ans.b and d
333.two files may be joined into a third file if they have
a.row in common
b.field in common
c.no records with the same value in the common field
d.both (b) and (c)
ans.b
334 .a functional dependency of the form x—>y is trivial if
a.y ⊆ x 
b.x ⊆ y
c.y ⊂ x
d.x ⊂y and y ⊂x
ans.a
335. any binary relation is in
a. 1NF
B. 2NF
C. 3NF
D. B CNF
ANS. C
336.Functional dependencies are a generalization of
a.key dependencies
b.relation dependemcies
c.database dependencies
d.none of these
ans a.

337. A condition that occurs when two transactions wait for each other to unlock data is known as a(n)
(a)  shared lock                                      (b)  exclusive lock                          (c)  two-phase lock
(d)  deadlock                                         (e)  Timestamp.
ans.d
338. What are the correct features of a distributed database?
(a)   Is always connected to the internet
(b)   Always requires more than three machines
(c)   Users see the data in one global schema.
(d)   Have to specify the physical location of the data when an update is done
(e)   All DBMS have to be homogenous.
ans. c
339. Which of the following is a function of a distributed DBMS?
a.Distributed query processing
b.Replicated data management
c.Distributed data recovery
d.All of these.
ans.d

340.Which of the following refers to the operation of copying and maintaining database objects in multiple physical databases belonging to a distributed system?
a.Backup
b.Recovery
c.Replication
d.All of these.
ans. c

341.A transaction processor is responsible for
a.Receiving and processing only local applications’ data requests
b.Receiving and processing only remote applications’ data requests
c.Receiving and processing both local and remote applications’ data requests
d.None of the above.
ans. c

342.Which of the following statements is false?
a.A transaction manager is responsible for receiving and processing both local and remote applications’ data requests
b.A data processor stores and retrieves data located at that site
c.The DM and the TM both have the same responsibility
d.None of the above.
ans. c


343.Local autonomy means
a.Local query will be processed locally
b.Local data will be accessed by local site only
c.Local DBA is sole authority of local data
d.Each site is a DBMS in its own right.
ans.b

344. A sophisticated locking mechanism known as 2-phase locking which includes Growing phase and .......
a. Shrinking Phase
b. Release phase
C. Commit phase
d. Acquire Phase
ans. a
345. .......... servers which is widely used in relational database systems.
a. Data servers
b. Transaction servers
C. Query servers
d. Client servers
ans. b. 
346.for committing a transaction, the DBMS might discard all the records.
a. after image
b. before image
c. log
d. redo log
ans. b

347.for transactions per rollback segment is derived from .....
A. Db_Block_Buffers
B. Processes
C. shared_Pool_size
D. buffers
ans.b
